<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
<title>
Jenkins LTS Changelog
</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable
</link>
<atom:link href="https://gilesgas.github.io/jenkins.io/WEBSITE-453-update-main-blue-ocean-and-getting-started-pages/changelog-stable/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<description>
Changelog for Jenkins LTS releases
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000
</lastBuildDate>
<!-- starting partial changelog-changes.xml.haml -->
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.89.3</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.89.3
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Make sure detached plugins (plugins whose functionality used to be part of Jenkins itself) are installed when upgrading Jenkins past the version at which the plugin was detached.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Make the system property &lt;code&gt;hudson.consoleTailKB&lt;/code&gt; actually work.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix a performance regression in Jenkins 2.86 due to lock contention in &lt;code&gt;ExtensionList&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent setup wizard from hanging when the two provided passwords differ, instead show a validation error.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent concurrent installation of Maven on the same node to prevent problems.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent potential &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; when migrating the default "All View" name for a "My Views" user property.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Cache permission names, allowing Jenkins to recover faster after "stop-the-world" Java GC pauses.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Improve user lookup performance, for example from Git changelog calculation.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.89.3
</guid>
<pubDate>
Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.89.2</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.89.2
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Security:
Security fixes.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.89.2
</guid>
<pubDate>
Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.89.1</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.89.1
</link>
<description>
&lt;strong&gt;Changes since 2.89:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Recover from legacy user configuration folders with &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; characters that are not part of hex escape sequences. (Regression in 2.89)

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Fix &lt;em&gt;Download from java.sun.com&lt;/em&gt; installation method for JDK for downloads requiring an Oracle login after change to the Oracle site.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update Remoting from 3.13 to 3.14 in order to apply various performance and stability improvements.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update Windows Agent Installer from 1.9.1 to 1.9.2: Do not try to update &lt;code&gt;jenkins-slave.exe&lt;/code&gt; on Unix agents when they connect.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent caching of captcha on the login form.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes since 2.73.3:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
&lt;em&gt;Launch agent via execution of command on the master&lt;/em&gt; has been moved to a new &lt;em&gt;Command Launcher&lt;/em&gt; plugin and integrated with the &lt;em&gt;Script Security&lt;/em&gt; plugin.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Prevent core or plugin code from mistakenly attempting to serialize jobs, builds, and users except in their intended top-level XML file positions, preventing a class of serious deserialization-related errors.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Developer: Fix &lt;code&gt;TimeDuration&lt;/code&gt; time unit handling and its incorrect usage. &lt;code&gt;TimeDuration&lt;/code&gt; uses milliseconds as the default unit. It was supposed to parse &lt;code&gt;sec&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;secs&lt;/code&gt; suffix to interpret the number as seconds, but that never worked.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Upgrade Stapler library from 1.250 to 1.253.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Stapler 1.252: Prevent file handle leak in &lt;code&gt;LargeText#GzipAwareSession&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Stapler 1.252: Restore ability to attach views to interfaces (regression in Jenkins 2.46).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Stapler 1.253: Servlet 3.1 support, improved Blue Ocean performance and changes of interest to plugin developers.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Update Remoting to improve stability and diagnosability.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Disable obsolete JNLP, JNLP2, and CLI protocols on new Jenkins installations during Setup Wizard.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Restart agent communication related threads on both master and agents when encountering an unhandled exception, if possible, to improve stability.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Default the built-in Jenkins Update Center URL to &lt;code&gt;https://updates.jenkins.io&lt;/code&gt; instead of obsolete HTTP endpoint. &lt;strong&gt;This requires a JRE compatible with &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/docs/certificate-compatibility/#known-compatible"&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;, e.g. Oracle JRE 8u101.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Moved Jenkins agent runtime to &lt;code&gt;agent.jar&lt;/code&gt; file name, and deprecate (but still support) use of legacy &lt;code&gt;slave.jar&lt;/code&gt;. Introduce the &lt;code&gt;AGENTJAR_URL&lt;/code&gt; environment variable as replacement for &lt;code&gt;SLAVEJAR_URL&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Improve error reporting when failing to archive artifacts.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Enable &lt;code&gt;cc.xml&lt;/code&gt; to export jobs in folders recursively when accessed with a query parameter named &lt;code&gt;recursive&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Add new administrative monitor warning users about disabled CSRF protection.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Commons Codec library upgraded from 1.8 to 1.9.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Agents JVM must be 1.8+ and a clear message is shown in connection logs if it is not.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Add sidebar link to create new view.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.89.1
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 6 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.73.3</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.73.3
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Security:
Security fixes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Fix &lt;em&gt;Download from java.sun.com&lt;/em&gt; installation method for JDK for downloads requiring an Oracle login after change to the Oracle site.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix potential HTTP 414 error in form validation of long Batch/Shell tool installer scripts.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Properly display agent launch arguments when using nested launch methods.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Disconnect node on ping timeout instead of leaving the channel half open.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Avoid a possible server-side timeout on long-running CLI commands using plain HTTP mode by sending periodic pings from the client.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.73.3
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 8 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.73.2</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.73.2
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Security:
Important security fixes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Fix random failures to use passphrase-protected ed25519 SSH private keys (regression in 2.73).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Update Remoting library from 3.10 to 3.10.2 to fix regression in Jenkins 2.68 when using non-writable home directories.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Update Remoting from 3.10 to 3.10.2 to improve stability and diagnosability.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.73.2
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.73.1</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.73.1
</link>
<description>
&lt;strong&gt;Changes since 2.73:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update Windows service wrapper from 2.1.0 to 2.1.2 and Windows Agent Installer from 1.9 to 1.9.1.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Log name of the executor thread that died to improve diagnosability.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent caching of the item categories list by the browser to prevent stale data.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Improve robustness of the reverse build trigger ("Build after other projects are built").

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Include culprits in XML and JSON API again (regression in 2.60).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Button to validate proxy configuration in Manage Plugins now works correctly with NTLM authorization.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes since 2.60.3:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Upgrade Groovy from 2.4.8 to 2.4.11.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Integration of Winstone 4: Upgrade bundled Jetty from 9.2.15.v20160210 to 9.4.5.v20170502. &lt;strong&gt;This removes support for the deprecated SPDY protocol. The &lt;tt&gt;--spdy&lt;/tt&gt; parameter has been removed accordingly and Jenkins may refuse to start if it's set.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Jetty 9.4.5: Prevent the &lt;i&gt;400 Bad Host header&lt;/i&gt; error for &lt;code&gt;HttpChannelOverHttp&lt;/code&gt; when operating behind reverse proxy.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Winstone 4.1: Add Jetty HTTP/2 connector and corresponding options for Winstone-Jetty.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Update Remoting from 3.7 to 3.10 adding opt-in support for work directories and improving logging in Jenkins agents.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Enable Remoting work directories by default for newly created agents launched via JNLP (Java Web Start Launcher).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
SSHD Module 2.0: Update from SSHD Core 0.14.0 to Apache MINA SSHD 1.6.0 in Jenkins core and Jenkins CLI.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
SSHD Module 2.0: Enable aes192ctr and aes256ctr ciphers if JVM supports unlimited-strength encryption.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update WinP from 1.24 to 1.25 to improve performance and diagnostics of issues like &lt;a href="https://issues.jenkins-ci.org/browse/JENKINS-30782"&gt;JENKINS-30782&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Update jnr-posix from 3.0.1 to 3.0.41 to pick up improvements and fixes in the POSIX platforms support.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Freestyle projects may now list Pipeline jobs as downstream and trigger them, without needing to use the Parameterized Trigger plugin or reverse triggers ("Build after other projects are built").
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Internal: Define enabling/disabling in &lt;code&gt;ParameterizedJob&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;AbstractProject&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Fixed Pipeline compatibility for a number of CLI commands (&lt;tt&gt;delete-builds&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;list-changes&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;console&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;set-build-description&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt&gt;set-build-display-name&lt;/tt&gt;), as well as some issues affecting error reporting in other commands when used with Pipeline.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Enable simpler syntax for &lt;code&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt; build trigger in pipelines.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Minor optimization to queue maintenance routines and printing of console notes, mainly for the benefit of Pipeline node blocks.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
If you have the Authorize Project plugin installed and configured, its configuration will now be treated as final with respect to the behavior of &lt;em&gt;Job/Build&lt;/em&gt; checks from &lt;strong&gt;Build other projects&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Build after other projects are built&lt;/strong&gt;. Formerly, if a &lt;strong&gt;Per-project configurable Build Authorization&lt;/strong&gt; was enabled globally but some projects did not specify an &lt;strong&gt;Authorization&lt;/strong&gt;, the two aforementioned checks would automatically fall back to checking as anonymous (typically denying build permission). To restore the former behavior, explicitly configure a &lt;strong&gt;Project default Build Authorization&lt;/strong&gt; to be &lt;strong&gt;Run as anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;. Note that this will affect all build-scoped permission checks, including for example &lt;em&gt;Agent/Build&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Internal API: &lt;code&gt;Tasks.getAuthenticationOf&lt;/code&gt; now honors authentication contributed by &lt;code&gt;QueueItemAuthenticatorProvider&lt;/code&gt; extensions.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Moved agent port and protocol configuration out of "security" (authentication and authorization) block in Configure Global Security.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Don't reload user records from disk unless explicitly requested to improve performance of user record access.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Plugin Development: Jenkins now no longer publishes a &lt;code&gt;war-for-test&lt;/code&gt; artifact. Plugins using 2.64 or a later version of Jenkins (including 2.73.1) as baseline need to use plugin parent POM 2.30 or later.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.73.1
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.60.3</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.60.3
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Contributions to the PATH environment variable could result in malformed values on agents on a platform different from master's.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Robustness improvements related to agent connections.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
JNLP for launching agents now requests Java 8.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent &lt;tt&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Jenkins#getRootURL()&lt;/code&gt; while the instance is not fully loaded yet.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix &lt;tt&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/tt&gt; when calculating culprits.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
The &lt;code&gt;reload-configuration&lt;/code&gt; CLI command now waits until the reload is finished, and returns an error code if the reload failed.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Remove the "JNLP" protocol references from the TCP Agent Listener log messages.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.60.3
</guid>
<pubDate>
Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.60.2</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.60.2
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Allow overriding the Jenkins session ID suffix so it doesn't change on every restart, possibly resulting in too many cookies.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Add documentation for time zone specification for cron patterns (e.g. SCM polling).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Do not submit form when pressing &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; in the plugin manager's filter field.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Jenkins failed to perform some cleanup tasks, including saving the build queue, if stopped via REST &lt;tt&gt;/exit&lt;/tt&gt;, CLI &lt;tt&gt;shutdown&lt;/tt&gt;, or when restarting from &lt;em&gt;Install as Windows Service&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Don't check whether disabled administrative monitors are active or not on the &lt;em&gt;Manage Jenkins&lt;/em&gt; page.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
When starting the &lt;code&gt;jenkins.war&lt;/code&gt; directly, properly check for Java 8 as minimum instead of Java 7 before proceeding.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; when calling &lt;code&gt;restart&lt;/code&gt; CLI command (regression in 2.57).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent possible &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; when listing remote directories using the &lt;code&gt;FilePath#list()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FilePath#listDirectories()&lt;/code&gt; APIs.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.60.2
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.60.1</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.60.1
</link>
<description>
&lt;strong&gt;Changes since 2.60:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix for &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; while initiating some SSH connections (regression in 2.59).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes since 2.46.3:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
&lt;strong&gt;Jenkins (master and agents) now requires Java 8 to run.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Update Groovy to 2.4.8 to address memory leak issue. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pipeline: Groovy&lt;/em&gt; needs to be upgraded to 2.28 or higher to prevent regressions.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Upgrade the Windows Agent Installer module from 1.6 to 1.7. This change picks major updates in Windows service management logic.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Windows services: Upgrade the bundled &lt;a href="https://github.com/kohsuke/winsw"&gt;Windows Service Wrapper&lt;/a&gt; from 1.18 to 2.0.2.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Windows services: Enable &lt;a href="https://github.com/kohsuke/winsw/blob/master/doc/extensions/runawayProcessKiller.md"&gt;Runaway Process Killer&lt;/a&gt; by default in new Agent and Master installations.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Windows services: Enable auto-upgrade of Remoting on newly installed agents if they are connected by HTTPS.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Windows services: Add support of shared directories mapping in Windows agent services.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Windows services: Integrate various stability and performance fixes in &lt;a href="https://github.com/kohsuke/winsw"&gt;Windows Service Wrapper&lt;/a&gt; from 1.18 to 2.0.2. There are many fixes around configuration options and process termination.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Packaging: Do not invoke recursive &lt;code&gt;chown&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;JENKINS_HOME&lt;/code&gt; during the RPM post-install step unless owned by a different user.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Use case-insensitive search by default for new and anonymous users.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Searching in the Build History widget takes into account user preferences (case sensitivity by default).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Allow searching by build parameter values in the Build History widget.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update the Trilead SSH library to get support of new Mac, Key, and Key Exchange Algorithms.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
When creating temporary files, use the &lt;code&gt;jenkins&lt;/code&gt; prefix instead of the old &lt;code&gt;hudson&lt;/code&gt; one.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update German, French and Russian localizations.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Removed localizations with very low coverage: Albanian, Basque, Belarusian, Bengali, Esperanto, Galician, Georgian, Gujarati, Hindi, Icelandic, Indonesian, Irish, Kannada, Macedonian, Marathi, Mongolian, Occitan, Punjabi, Sinhala, Tamil, Telugu, Thai.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Internal API: Add the ability for &lt;code&gt;ItemListener&lt;/code&gt; to veto copy operations; make &lt;code&gt;Run#compareTo&lt;/code&gt; work across jobs; save &lt;code&gt;Jenkins&lt;/code&gt; after calling &lt;code&gt;setSecurityRealm&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;setAuthorizationStrategy&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.60.1
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.46.3</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.46.3
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
If an exception is thrown while rendering an HTTP response, just log the stack trace on the server side, without trying to send an error page to the client.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Setup wizard gets into bad state when failures like network issues happen.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Catch and log &lt;code&gt;RuntimeException&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Computer#setNode()&lt;/code&gt; when updating the Computer list.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix &lt;tt&gt;AccessDeniedException&lt;/tt&gt; in "Build after other projects are built" when user has Discover permission but not Read.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; when a non-existent default view is specified in &lt;em&gt;Configure System&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Properly handle saving system configuration when disabling all, or all but one, administrative monitors.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Remove links in stack traces to the &lt;tt&gt;stacktrace.jenkins-ci.org&lt;/tt&gt; service that has been shut down.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Ensure that &lt;code&gt;Cloud.PROVISION&lt;/code&gt; is properly initialized during the configuration loading.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Migrate legacy users only once per restart to improve performance of the user retrieval logic.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent rare &lt;code&gt;NullPointerException&lt;/code&gt; if an admin user is created in the setup wizard after first disabling CSRF protection.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.46.3
</guid>
<pubDate>
Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.46.2</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.46.2
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Security:
Important security fixes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Non-Remoting-based CLI.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Disable SSH server by default.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
&lt;code&gt;Computer#addAction&lt;/code&gt; would throw an &lt;code&gt;UnsupportedOperationException&lt;/code&gt; since Jenkins 2.30. Such a call site was released in SSH Slaves Plugin 1.15 for SECURITY-161.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Search results page did not correctly encode query parameters.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
When validating a cron expression, consider the specified time zone.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Do not display a warning when an SCM trigger has no schedules (either to disable SCM post-commit hooks, or to enable them without polling).

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix performance issue in deduplication of lists of tool installers.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.46.2
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.46.1</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.46.1
</link>
<description>
&lt;strong&gt;Changes since 2.46:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent file descriptor leaks when Windows Service installer fails to read data from the service startup log.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Update Remoting from 3.5 to 3.7 in order to prevent file descriptor leaks on agents in the case of multiple connection attempts.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Exceptions during Jenkins cleanup step should not block restart.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Cryptic error message when loading JnlpSlaveAgentProtocol4.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Developer: Snapshot builds of plugins that had dependencies on other snapshot builds were not having their version numbers compared correctly.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Do not attempt to find the next occurrence of an impossible date such as June 31st in validation of trigger schedules.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Remoting 3.5: Stability improvements.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Remove invalid translations in Slovene
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Remoting 3.5: Add option to specify the Remoting protocol to use on the client.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Use of the remote API to create items in views (&lt;tt&gt;/view/…/createItem&lt;/tt&gt;) didn't actually add items to views since Jenkins 2.22.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Remoting 3.5: Remoting clients now accept lowercase (HTTP 2) headers sent by reverse proxies.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Windows service restart did not retain build queue.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes since 2.32.3:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update the &lt;a href="https://github.com/jenkinsci/sshd-module"&gt;SSHD module&lt;/a&gt; from 1.7 to 1.8. The change disables obsolete Ciphers: AES128CBC, TripleDESCBC, and BlowfishCBC.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Enable the JNLP4 agent protocol by default.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Allow defining agent ping interval and ping timeout in seconds. It can be done via the &lt;code&gt;hudson.slaves.ChannelPinger.pingIntervalSeconds&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hudson.slaves.ChannelPinger.pingTimeoutSeconds&lt;/code&gt; system properties.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Print stack traces in logical order, with the most important part on top.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Reduce size of Jenkins WAR file by not storing identical copies of &lt;code&gt;remoting.jar&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;slave.jar&lt;/code&gt; there.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Do not print warnings about undefined parameters when &lt;code&gt;hudson.model.ParametersAction.keepUndefinedParameters&lt;/code&gt; property is set to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Increase the &lt;code&gt;JENKINS_HOME&lt;/code&gt; disk space threshold from 1 GB to 10 GB left. The warning will be shown only if more than 90% of the disk is utilized.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Delete obsolete pinning UI.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Use project-specific validation URL for SCM Trigger, so &lt;code&gt;H&lt;/code&gt; is handled correctly in preview.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Failure to serialize a single &lt;code&gt;Action&lt;/code&gt; could cause an entire REST export response to fail. Upgraded to Stapler 1.250 with a fix.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Add Usage Statistics section to the global configuration to make it easier to find.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Allow &lt;tt&gt;groovy&lt;/tt&gt; CLI command via SSH CLI.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.46.1
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.32.3</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.32.3
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Display an informative message, rather than a Groovy exception, when &lt;code&gt;View#getItems&lt;/code&gt; fails.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Don't try to set Agent Port when it is enforced, breaking form submission.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Don't add all group names as HTTP headers on "access denied" pages, possibly breaking reverse proxies due to very large headers.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Fix handling of the &lt;tt&gt;POST&lt;/tt&gt; flag in &lt;code&gt;ManagementLink&lt;/code&gt;s within the Manage Jenkins page.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
&lt;code&gt;IllegalStateException&lt;/code&gt; from Winstone when making certain requests with access logging enabled.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Do not fail to write a log file just because something deleted the parent directory.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.32.3
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 1 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.32.2</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.32.2
</link>
<description>
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Security:
Important security fixes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Support displaying of warnings from the update site in the plugin manager and in administrative monitors.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Correctly state that Jenkins will refuse to load plugins whose dependencies are not satisfied in plugin manager.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
The &lt;tt&gt;install-plugin&lt;/tt&gt; CLI command now correctly installs plugins when multiple file arguments are specified.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Prevent the &lt;code&gt;ClassNotFoundException: javax.servlet.ServletException&lt;/code&gt; error when invoking shell tasks on remote agents.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Properties were not passed to Maven command by Maven build step when the &lt;em&gt;Inject Build Variables&lt;/em&gt; flag was not set.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Job configuration submission now does not fail when there is no parameters property.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Update Remoting to 3.4 in order to properly terminate the channel in the case &lt;code&gt;Errors&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Exception&lt;/code&gt;s.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
&lt;em&gt;Check for Updates&lt;/em&gt; button in the Plugin Manager was hidden in the &lt;em&gt;Updates&lt;/em&gt; tab when there was no plugins updates available.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
SSHD Module: Handshake was failing (wrong shared secret) 1 out of 256 times due to &lt;a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SSHD-330"&gt;SSHD-330&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Performance: Use bulk change when submitting Job configurations to minimize the number of sequential &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; write operations.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Jobs were hanging during process termination on the Solaris 11 Intel platform, regression in 2.20.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Restore option value for setting build result to unstable when loading shell and batch build steps from disk.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Update to Winstone 3.2 to support ad-hoc certificate generation on Java 8 (using unsupported APIs). &lt;strong&gt;This option is deprecated and will be removed in a future release.&lt;/strong&gt; We strongly recommend you create self-signed certificates yourself and use &lt;tt&gt;--httpsKeyStore&lt;/tt&gt; and related options instead.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.32.2
</guid>
<pubDate>
Wed, 1 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jenkins 2.32.1</title>
<link>
https://jenkins.io/changelog-stable//#v2.32.1
</link>
<description>
&lt;strong&gt;Changes since 2.32:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major Bug:
Prevent early deallocation of process references by Garbage Collector when starting a remote process. It was sometimes causing build failures with messages like &lt;code&gt;FATAL: Invalid object ID 184 iuota=187&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;java.lang.Exception: Object was recently deallocated&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
Redirect to login page in the case of authorisation error when checking connectivity to the Update Center.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
WinP 1.24: Native class now tries loading DLLs from the temporary location.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bug:
WinP 1.24: WinP sometimes kills wrong processes when using &lt;code&gt;killRecursive()&lt;/code&gt;. It was likely impacting process termination on Windows agents and sometimes leading to BSoD.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notable changes since 2.19.4:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Upgrade Remoting to version 3.1 with &lt;a href="https://github.com/jenkinsci/remoting/blob/master/docs/protocols.md#jnlp4-connect"&gt;JNLP4-connect protocol&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://github.com/jenkinsci/remoting/blob/master/docs/remoting-3-compatibility.md"&gt;Compatibility notes are available here&lt;/a&gt;. Notably, it is no longer possible to use JDK 6 for the Maven project type, as communication with the Maven process uses Remoting, and it now requires Java 7.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Major RFE:
Show notification with popup on most pages when administrative monitors are active.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Allow disabling/enabling administrative monitors on Configure Jenkins form.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Ask for confirmation before canceling/aborting runs.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Prompt user whether to add the job to the current view.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Allow &lt;code&gt;CommandInterpreter&lt;/code&gt; build steps to set a build result as &lt;em&gt;Unstable&lt;/em&gt; via the return code. Shell and Batch build steps now support this feature.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
RFE:
Internal: Upgrade Stapler library from 1.243 to 1.246 with fixes required for the Blue Ocean project. Changes are listed &lt;a href="https://github.com/stapler/stapler/compare/stapler-parent-1.243...stapler-parent-1.246"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">
jenkins-2.32.1
</guid>
<pubDate>
Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
</item>

<!-- ending partial changelog-changes.xml.haml -->
</channel>
</rss>
